George Korson Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound recordings
  - Sound recording (interviews), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR062)
    - Michael J. Burke, September 12, 1957
      Recorded at Burke's home, 104 West Hancock St., St. Clair, Pennsylvania.
    - Mrs. Water Lash, September 18, 1957
      Recorded at her home, 324 Laurel St., Minersville, Schuylkill County, Pennsylvania. AFC 2003/011: SR058 contains an abridged version of this recording.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR063)
    - Charles Henry "Mule" Haas, September 22, 1957
      Recorded at the home of John Mayers, Llewellyn Rd., Minersville, Pennsylvania. Haas also lived on Llewellyn Rd., Minersville, Pennsylvania. AFC 2003/011: SR060 contains an abridged version of this recording.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR064)
    - John Foster Stutzman, September 20, 1957
      Recorded at Stutzman's store, Donaldson, Pennsylvania.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR065)
    - William "Pop" Sholley, October 5, 1957
      Sholley sings in Pennsylvania German. Recorded at the home of Ralph M. Hyle, "Fair Winds," Bird Hill Rd., Pine Grove, Pennsylvania. Sholley was from Lebanon, Pennsylvania. The first part is duplicated on AFC 2003/011: SR058, with the balance duplicated on AFC 2003/011: SR059.
  - Sound recording (interviews), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR066)
    All interviews were recorded at the Williamsport Technical Institute, Williamsport, Pennsylvania.
    - John Gregar, July 1, 1958
      John Gregar's father was Steve Gregar. John Gregar lived on Bloomingrove Rd., Williamsport, Pennsylvania.
    - Ralph Schardt, July 1, 1958
    - William Miller, July 1, 1958
      Miller was from Saltzburg, Pennsylvania.
    - Nick A. Battiste, July 1, 1958
    - Kenneth Carl, July 1, 1958
    - Jim Bressler, July 1, 1958
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR067)
    - Patrick J. Lynch, August 28, 1958
      Ralph Hayes, of Washington, is with Korson. Recorded at the home of Mr. and Mrs. Patrick J. Lynch, 602 Montgomery St., Laurel, MD.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR068)
    - John Foster Stutzman; Dr. Wayne Broehl, October 30, 1958
      Broehl (Dartmouth College) is with Korson. Recorded at Stutzman's store, Donaldson, Pennsylvania.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR069)
    - Steve Lee; Sam Eskin; John Putnam; John Holt, March 31, 1962
      Recorded at the home of Fletcher Collins, Pennyroyal Farm, Staunton, Virginia
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR070)
    - Fletcher Collins; Margaret Collins, March 31, 1962
      The tape housing has "Putnam," with a question mark elsewhere; "John Putnam" appears on the take-up reel. Recorded at the home of Fletcher Collins, Pennyroyal Farm, Staunton, Virginia.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR071)
    - Rex Lauck; J. McCarthy; George Korson, November 22, 1965
      Continued on AFC 2003/011: SR072.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR072)
    - Rex Lauck; J. McCarthy; George Korson, November 22, 1965
      Continued from AFC 2003/011: SR071.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel (master): analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR073)
    - Mrs. Margarite Coleman; Leonard Murphy; Jack Murphy, October 15, 1966
      The subjects are three of the four children of John A. Murphy, Dickson City, Pennsylvania, coal miner/singer. Recorded at the sound studios, Washington, D.C.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR074)
    - Albert H. Gerberich, Sr., March 9, 1957
      Continued on AFC 2003/011: SR075. Recorded at the home of Gerberich's son, Dr. Albert H. Gerberich, Jr., 7912 Radnor Rd., Bethesda, MD.
  - Sound recording (interview) (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR075)
    - Albert H. Gerberich, Sr., March 9, 1957
      Continued from AFC 2003/011: SR075; continued on AFC 2003/011: SR076. Recorded at the home of Gerberich's son, Dr. Albert H. Gerberich, Jr., 7912 Radnor Rd., Bethesda, MD.
  - Sound recording (interview) (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR076)
    - Albert H. Gerberich, Sr., March 9, 1957
      Continued from AFC 2003/011: SR074-SR075. Recorded at the home of Gerberich's son, Dr. Albert H. Gerberich, Jr., 7912 Radnor Rd., Bethesda, MD.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR078)
    - Mrs. W.R. Buchanan
      Recorded in Heaton, NC. LWO 2295, WO 26756; AFC 2003/011: SR078-085 are part of this work order (eight reels, total). At about 28:55 the speed changes. The recording may have been dubbed from sound disc recordings.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR079)
    - Children's Songs, Carnegie
      LWO 2295, WO 26757, Reel 22. May have been dubbed from discs.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR080)
    - Children's Songs, Carnegie
      LWO 2295, WO 26758; listed as Reel 3 of 3. May have been dubbed from discs.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR081)
    - Children's LP (reference tape)
      LWO 2295, WO 26860. African American singing for majority (all?) of recording; may have hand-clapping songs included.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, single track, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR082)
    - Children's LP (reference tape)
      Miss Terrell; John Lomax. Korson can be heard on parts of the recording. LWO 2295, WO 26863 or 26865
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR083)
    - Children's Game Songs (reference tape)
      LWO 2295, WO 26931.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR084)
    - Children's Songs L-49-A (1 of 2)
      Possibly L49, "The Ballad Hunter, Parts I and II."
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR085)
    - Children's Songs L-49-B (2 of 2)
  - Sound recording, on 1 side of 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR086)
    - Bituminous Miner's Songs / Coal Dust Songs (1 of 2)
  - Sound recording, on 1 side of 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR087)
    - Bituminous Miner's Songs / Coal Dust Songs (2 of 2)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR088)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (1 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR089)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (2 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR090)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (3 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR091)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (4 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR092)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (5 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR093)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (6 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR094)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (7 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR095)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs (8 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR096)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs: The Tenderfoot; Closed Shop Blues (9 of 9)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR097)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs
      Copy of original recordings.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR098)
    - Bituminous Miners' Songs
      The documentation indicates these are "coal mining songs, mostly bituminous."
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR099)
    - Coal Miner's [sic] Folksongs (from the George Korson Collection), sung by Joe Glazer, April 5, 1962
      "Rough copy" of original recording.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (audio book): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR100)
    Recorded by Library of Congress, Division of the Blind, circa 1962. The number 3199-4-1 appears on the take-up reel. Jane Weatherford may be the reader.
    - Side A
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 1, side 1)
    - Side B
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 1, side 2)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (audio book): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR101)
    Recorded by Library of Congress, Division of the Blind, circa 1962. The number 3199-4-2 appears on the take-up reel. Jane Weatherford may be the reader.
    - Side A
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 2, side 1)
    - Side B
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 2, side 2)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (audio book): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR102)
    Recorded by Library of Congress, Division of the Blind, circa 1962. The number 3199-4-3 appears on the take-up reel. Jane Weatherford may be the reader.
    - Side A
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 3, side 1)
    - Side B
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 3, side 2)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel (audio book): analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR103)
    Recorded by Library of Congress, Division of the Blind, circa 1962. The number 3199-4-4 appears on the take-up reel. Jane Weatherford may be the reader.
    - Side A
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 4, side 1)
    - Side B
      - Emrich, Marion Vallet, and George Korson, Child's Book of Folklore (reel 4, side 2)
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR104)
    - "Panorama - U.S.A.," circa 1962
      Interview with George Korson, and a collection of folk songs. Les Higbie, host; Leo Beldac (or Les Beldock), interviewer. Recorded in Washington, D.C., and broadcast on Voice of America. The date may be the broadcast date.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR105)
    - "From Here to Sunday," February-March 1961
      Review of George Korson's book Black Rock; Ed Cray, reviewer. The first 10 seconds of the recording is backwards (recorded on the other side of the tape). For broadcast: KPFK (2-17-61); KPFA (2-24-61); WBAI (3-61). Dub copy.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR106)
    - "Folk Music of the Coal Mines," November 8, 1965
      Includes an interview with George Korson. The first 10 seconds of the recording is backwards (recorded on the other side of the tape). "Folk Music of the Coal Mines" was broadcast on the radio as part of the program, "American Scene," on Voice of America.
  - Sound recording, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, double track; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR107)
    Probably LP 61, from the AFS LP series. Reference tape of composites.
    - Railroad Songs, LP 61
  - Sound recording December 10, 1975, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR108)
    - Joe Glazer concert, December 10, 1975
      Glazer's album "Down in a coal mine" was dedicated to George Korson. Mary Barrett, librarian King's College, introduces Joe Glazer. Rae Korson was an alumna of King's College; money for use of Korson-collected funds went to buy books and records for the George Korson Folklore Archive; Angus Gillespie also made an introduction.
  - "Folk Music of the Coal Mines," February 28, 1973, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR109)
    Recorded in Washington, D.C.
    - Side A
      "Folk Music of the Coal Mines" was broadcast on the radio as part of the program, "American Scene," on Voice of America.
      - Archie Green, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (1 of 3)
    - Side B
      - Archie Green, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (2 of 3)
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR110)
    - Archie Green, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (3 of 3), February 28, 1973
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR111)
    - Wayland D. Hand, interviewed by Angus Gillespie, November 1, 1974
      Recorded in Portland, Oregon.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR112)
    - Frank Hoffman, interviewed by Angus Gillespie, November 2, 1974
      After the 20-minute mark, the tape speeds up (the recordist changed the recording speed). Recorded in Portland, Oregon.
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR113)
    Daughter and son-in-law of Rae and George Korson.
    - Side A
      - Betsy Korson Glazier and Harold Glazier, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (1 of 3)
    - Side B
      - Betsy Korson Glazier and Harold Glazier, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (2 of 3)
  - Sound recording (interview), 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR114)
    - Betsy Korson Glazier and Harold Glazier, interviewed by Angus Gillespie (3 of 3)
      See note for AFC 2003/011: SR113.
    - Jane Weatherford, circa 1967
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR115)
    Original ID #1
    - Side A
      - Down, Down, Down
        Performed by Bill Keating
    - Side B
      - Down, Down, Down
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR116)
    Original ID #2
    - Side A
      - The Driver Boys of Wadesville Shaft
    - Side B
      - My Wee Coal Hole
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR117)
    Original ID #3
    - Side A
      - October on Mt. Laffee's Hills
    - Side B
      - Down In A Coal Mine
        Performed by Dan Walsh. See AFC 2003/011: SR192.
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR118)
    Original ID #4. All songs performed by Dan Walsh.
    - Side A
      - The Pretty Maid Milking Her Goat
    - My Sweetheart's The Mule In The Mine
    - Side B
      - A Celebrated Workingman
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR119)
    Original ID #5
    - Side A
      - The Miner's Doom
        Performed by Dan Walsh
    - Side B
      - The Old Miner's Refrain
        Performed by Dan Walsh. See AFC 2003/011: SR120, SR132, SR144, and SR192.
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR120)
    Original ID #6
    - Side A
      - The Old Miner's Refrain
        Performed by Dan Walsh. See AFC 2003/011: SR119, SR132, SR144, and SR192.
    - Side B
      - Me Johnny Mitchell Man
        Performed by Jerry Byrne
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR121)
    Original ID #7
    - Side A
      - Johnny Mitchell's Train
    - Side B
      - When The Breaker Starts Up Full Time
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR122)
    Original ID #8
    - Side A
      - The Hungarian Ball
    - Side B
      - A Miner's Home Sweet Home
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR123)
    Original ID #9
    - Side A
      - The Sugar Notch Entombment
        Performed by Andrew Rada
    - Side B
      - John J. Curtis
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR124)
    Original ID #10
    - Side A
      - A Miner's Son
    - Side B
      - The Battlefields of France
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR125)
    Original ID #11
    - Side A
      - Clog Dancing
        Performed by Albert Morgan
    - Side B
      - The Shoofly
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR126)
    Original ID #12
    - Side A
      - Down In A Deep Hole
    - Side B
      - We're The Boys Who Get Out The Coal
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR127)
    Original ID #13
    - Side A
      - A Miner's Home Sweet Home
        Performed by Tom "Butch" O'Brien
    - Side B
      - Muff Lawlor, The Squealor
        Performed by Joe McCarthy
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR128)
    Original ID #14
    - Side A
      - Muff Lawlor, The Squealor
    - Side B
      - Lost Creek
        Performed by John Griffin
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR129)
    Original ID #15
    - Side A
      - Miner's Ballad
        Performed by Tom Barrett and Walter Roland
    - Side B
      - How Are You Gonna Get Them Back In The Mines
        Performed by Bill Hand
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR130)
    Original ID #16
    - Side A
      - The Broken Shovel
        Performed by Dan Brennan
    - Side B
      - The Hungarian Christening
        Performed by Donald Brennan
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR131)
    Original ID #17
    - Side A
      - The Jeanesville Mine Disaster (1891)
    - Side B
      - Jenkin Jenkins
        Performed by Tom Roberts
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR132)
    Original ID #18. See AFC 2003/011: SR119-120, SR144, and SR192.
    - Side A
      - The Old Miner's Refrain
    - Side B
      - The Old Miner's Refrain
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR133)
    Original ID #19
    - Side A
      - When The Breaker Starts Up Full Time
    - Side B
      - When The Breaker Starts Up Full Time
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR134)
    Original ID #20
    - Side A
      - The Door Boy's Last Goodbye
        Performed by Idris Jones
    - Side B
      - The Door Boy's Last Goodbye
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR135)
    Original ID #21
    - Side A
      - Down In A Coal Mine
        Performed by Morgan Jones
    - Side B
      - A Miner's Home Sweet Home
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR136)
    Original ID #22
    - Side A
      - A Miner's Home Sweet Home
    - Side B
      - When The Breaker Starts Up Full Time
        Performed by John J. Quinn
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR137)
    Original ID #23
    - Side A
      - The Mines of Avondale
    - Side B
      - The Driver Boy
        Performed by John J. Quinn. Recorded by George Korson in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania.
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR138)
    Original ID #XXIV
    - Side A
      - The Driver Boy
    - Side B
      - The Hungarian Christening
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR139)
    Original ID #XXV
    - Side A
      - The Hungarian Ball
        Recorded by George Korson in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania
    - Side B
      - The Door Boy's Last Goodbye
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR140)
    Original ID #I
    - Side A
      - Down, Down, Down
    - Side B
      - Me Johnny Mitchell Man
      - Fiddle Tune (The Boys on the Hill - a hornpipe)
        Performed by James Muldowney
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR141)
    Original ID #II
    - Side A
      - John J. Curtis
      - The Broken Shovel
    - Side B
      - When The Breaker Starts Up Full Time
      - Union Man
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR142)
    Original ID #III
    - Side A
      - The Mines of Avondale
    - Side B
      - The Shoo Fly
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR143)
    Original ID #IV
    - Side A
      - The Driver Boy
    - Side B
      - Down In A Coal Mine
      - Fiddle Tune (Rolling on the Rye Grass - a reel)
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR144)
    Original ID #V
    - Side A
      - Jenkin Jenkins
      - A Miner's Son
    - Side B
      - The Old Miner's Refrain
        Performed by Dan Walsh. See AFC 2003/011: SR119-120, SR132, and SR192.
      - Clog [Miner's Jig Dance?]
        The dancer is Mine Superintendant Stewart. See AFC 2003/011: SR192. AFC 2003/011: SR125 may be the same performance.
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 12 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR145)
    Original ID #VI
    - Side A
      - On Johnny Mitchell's Train
      - My Sweetheart's The Mule In The Mine
        Performed by Tom O'Brien
    - Side B
      - The Door Boy's Last Goodbye
  - Sound recording (musical performance), February 1, 1940, 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 10 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR146)
    Recorded in Columbus, Ohio. Original ID #1
    - Side A
      - Jolly Wee Miner Men
        Performed by Bob Stewart (Nova Scotia)
      - Arise Ye Nova Scotia Slaves
        Performed by Bob Stewart
    - Side B
      - Wild Rover
  - Sound recording (musical performance), 1 sound disc (lacquer on aluminum): analog; 10 in. (Item-id AFC 2003/011: SR147)
    - Side A
      - Roll Along United Miners
        Performed by Shakey Robertson
      - Are You From Bevan
        Performed by George Masavage
      - I Wonder When I'll Ever Have A Car Again
        Performed by George Masavage [?]
    - Side B
      - In New Glasgow I Was Born
      - The Miner's Grievance (recitation)
        Performed by Richard Brahosky